HOWARD LUAN

(902) 981-8090 | Howard@Luan.contact | https://www.linkedin.com/in/howardluan/ | Halifax, NS

SUMMARY

Knowledgeable and professional graduates in Technical Support role. Provided technical support and upgraded technological equipment for over 50 staff. Experience in explaining technical terms to non-technical users. Planned and created user documentation, such as manual, self-troubleshooting guides, system recommendation. Highly efficient, attention to detail with strong problem-solving, customer service and communication.

EXPERIENCE

Program Facilitator

January 2021 – Present

Code Ninjas Halifax

- Explained JavaScript, Lua, C# code concepts and algorithms to kids, from six to fourteen, helping them understand the concepts better and solve their problems in their games.
- Led and instructed multiple Roblox, Scratch and YouTube camps. Tasks include planning the curriculum, presenting, explaining, and helping participants with their content. Resulted in the increasing of returning kids to the programs.
- Created a Unity game used for promotions purpose and entertainment for kids, based on predeveloped characters and functions, as a motivation for kids to learn more and enjoy their time in the class.
- Welcomed and checked in kids to the class, provided customer service to parents and introduced the program to first-time parents and kids. Resulted in boosting the sign-up rate for the organization.

Desktop Support Technician

May 2022 - Dec 2022

Dalhousie University

- Installed, upgraded, tested technology equipment for over 50 offices, including laptops, printers, docking stations, cable organizations.
- Prepared, configurated, and installed new equipment for new employees, and guided the employees with the on-boarding process. Resulted in less technical support tickets from new employees.
- Provided in-person and remote technical support for over 50 staff members, including troubleshooting software, hardware and installation of driver. Received compliments from manager and employees for the knowledge and patience working with the employees.

Technical Operational Assistant

January 2022 – March 2022

Dalhousie University

- Created formal troubleshooting guide for common issues experienced by staff and frequently asked
 questions document for internal staff. Received compliments from supervisors and colleagues for
 the detail and format.
- Planned, installed, upgraded, tested technology equipment for staff, including laptops, printers, docking stations, cable organizations. Completed the implementation ahead of schedule by one week.

• Provided in-person and remote technical support for staff having issues with new equipment, including software, hardware, cables, and docks. Received compliments from directors and employees for the knowledge and patience in solving technical issues.

myDal User Experience Coordinator

September 2021 – December 2021

Dalhousie University

- Performed, reviewed, and reported on the usability of the internal department site and provided recommendations to improve the user experience for employees. Resulted in the implementation of the recommended report.
- Planned, drafted, and created user documentation for staff to perform usability testing for their site. Document included recruiting participants, scripting for a usability test, what to perform during usability test. Accepted by supervisor and later distributed for internal use.
- Reviewed, summarized, and reported on various usability testing tools and provided recommendation to the organization. Saved the subscription fees on usability testing tools.

Everybyte Digital Products Co-op:

June 2020 – August 2020

User-requirement analyst

- Participated in a team with four other members to create a prototype for a system that hires and manages Teaching Assistant at Dalhousie University.
- Prepared and interviewed with CBC, SimplyCast, Dalhousie Faculty of Computer Science to understand user requirements and provide a solution.
- Meetings every two days to discuss the project through Microsoft Teams while studying two courses remotely.
- Received the most vote for the best idea from fellow members in the company.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science, Co-op, Minor in Entrepreneurship & Innovation Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia 2018 – 2022

• Certificates: Communication Technologies & Cyber Security | Web & Mobile Development

SKILLS

Language				
English	Vietnamese	Chinese	Cantonese	
★★★★☆	****	***	★★★☆☆	
Technical				
HTML & CSS	JavaScript & ReactJS	Cloud Computing	UI & UX Design	Design Thinking
★★★★☆	***	****	***	****
Database System	PHP	Network Computing	g Android Studio	Java
$\star\star\star \star \Delta \Delta$	***	★★★★☆	★★★☆☆	***
Interpersonal				
Problem	Customer Service	Organization	Communication A	Adaptability
Solving				
****	★★★★☆	****	****	****